{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"the heart.",
					"the skin.",
					"the brain.",
					"the lungs."
				],
				"question": "To protect vital organs, the body compensates by directing blood flow away from organs that are more tolerant of low flow, such as:",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology"
			},
			"back": "the skin."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"apply pressure to the brachial artery.",
					"apply a tourniquet proximal to the wrist.",
					"administer high-flow supplemental oxygen.",
					"wrap the towel with pressure bandages."
				],
				"question": "A 20-year-old male has a large laceration to his wrist. He is holding a blood-soaked towel over the wound, but it continues to bleed rapidly. You should:",
				"source": "See Emergency Medical Care for Shock"
			},
			"back": "apply a tourniquet proximal to the wrist."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"whole blood.",
					"platelets.",
					"plasma.",
					"red blood cells."
				],
				"question": "Hypovolemic shock caused by severe burns is the result of a loss of:",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "plasma."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"hypoperfusion to the cells of the body.",
					"temporary dysfunction of a major organ.",
					"widespread constriction of the blood vessels.",
					"the bodyâ€™s maintenance of homeostasis."
				],
				"question": "Shock is the result of:",
				"source": "See Introduction"
			},
			"back": "hypoperfusion to the cells of the body."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Pallor",
					"Dizziness",
					"Hypotension",
					"Wheezing"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following clinical signs is unique to anaphylactic shock?",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "Wheezing"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Sensitized people will experience less severe reactions upon subsequent exposure.",
					"Anaphylactic shock occurs immediately after a person is sensitized to an allergen.",
					"Subsequent exposure after sensitization often produces a more severe reaction.",
					"Anaphylactic shock is caused by immune system failure due to a toxic exposure."
				],
				"question": "Which of the following statements regarding anaphylactic shock is correct?",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "Subsequent exposure after sensitization often produces a more severe reaction."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"spinal injury.",
					"ischemic stroke.",
					"severe infection.",
					"anaphylaxis."
				],
				"question": "All of the following conditions should make you suspect shock, EXCEPT:",
				"source": "See The Progression of Shock"
			},
			"back": "ischemic stroke."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"under complete control of the voluntary portion of the nervous system.",
					"circular muscular walls that regulate blood flow through the capillaries.",
					"responsible for constricting to compensate for decreased cell perfusion.",
					"capable of dilating in order to increase perfusion to crucial body organs."
				],
				"question": "Capillary sphincters are:",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology"
			},
			"back": "circular muscular walls that regulate blood flow through the capillaries."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Liver laceration",
					"Simple pneumothorax",
					"Spinal cord injury",
					"Cardiac tamponade"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following injuries would MOST likely cause obstructive shock?",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "Cardiac tamponade"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"A 23-year-old restless male with cool, clammy skin and tachycardia",
					"A 32-year-old male with anxiety and a systolic blood pressure of 110 mm Hg",
					"A 28-year-old female with pale skin and rapid, shallow respirations",
					"A 20-year-old female with absent radial pulses and dilated pupils"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following patients is in decompensated shock?",
				"source": "See The Progression of Shock"
			},
			"back": "A 20-year-old female with absent radial pulses and dilated pupils"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"absent peripheral pulses.",
					"cool and clammy skin.",
					"rapid, shallow breathing.",
					"restlessness or anxiety."
				],
				"question": "Clinical signs of compensated shock include all of the following, EXCEPT:",
				"source": "See The Progression of Shock"
			},
			"back": "absent peripheral pulses."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"septic shock.",
					"a local infection.",
					"pump failure.",
					"decompensated shock."
				],
				"question": "A 70-year-old female was recently discharged from the hospital following a total hip replacement. Today, she presents with restlessness, tachycardia, and a blood pressure of 90/64 mm Hg. Her skin is hot and moist. You should be MOST suspicious that she is experiencing:",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "septic shock."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"neurogenic shock.",
					"anaphylactic shock.",
					"septic shock.",
					"cardiogenic shock."
				],
				"question": "Pulmonary edema and impaired ventilation occur during:",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "cardiogenic shock."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"tachycardia.",
					"hypovolemia.",
					"hypothermia.",
					"diaphoresis."
				],
				"question": "In an acute injury setting, neurogenic shock is commonly accompanied by:",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "hypothermia."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"carbon dioxide.",
					"lactic acid.",
					"pyruvic acid.",
					"carbon monoxide."
				],
				"question": "One of the primary waste products of normal cellular metabolism that must be removed from the body by the lungs is:",
				"source": "See Pathophysiology"
			},
			"back": "carbon dioxide."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"widespread dilation of the blood vessels causes blood to pool in the vascular beds.",
					"temporary but severe vasodilation causes a decrease in blood supply to the brain.",
					"an injury causes restriction of the heart muscle and impairs its pumping function.",
					"severe bleeding causes tachycardia in order to distribute blood to the organs faster."
				],
				"question": "Distributive shock occurs when:",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "widespread dilation of the blood vessels causes blood to pool in the vascular beds."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"increased afterload.",
					"heart attack.",
					"poor contractility.",
					"increased preload."
				],
				"question": "Cardiogenic shock may result from all of the following, EXCEPT:",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "increased preload."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Liver laceration",
					"Excessive sweating",
					"Severe vomiting",
					"Repeated diarrhea"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following would MOST likely result in hemorrhagic shock?",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "Liver laceration"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"Decompression of the injured side of the chest",
					"Positive-pressure ventilation with a bag-valve mask",
					"Early administration of high-flow oxygen",
					"Rapid administration of intravenous fluids"
				],
				"question": "Which of the following is the ONLY action that can prevent death from a tension pneumothorax?",
				"source": "See Emergency Medical Care for Shock"
			},
			"back": "Decompression of the injured side of the chest"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-13-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": {
				"choices": [
					"massive vasoconstriction occurs distal to a spinal cord injury.",
					"failure of the nervous system causes widespread vasodilation.",
					"there is too much blood to fill a smaller vascular container.",
					"the spinal cord is severed and causes massive hemorrhaging."
				],
				"question": "Neurogenic shock occurs when:",
				"source": "See Types of Shock"
			},
			"back": "failure of the nervous system causes widespread vasodilation."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-13",
		"label": "Chapter 13"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}